

Himanshu Singh

Analyst



Professional Summary

Business and data analyst with 4 years of experience across diverse industries. Expertise in analysis and testing of business requirements to drive deployment of applications, business processes and system solutions. Highly analytical and detailed with documented track record in full software development life cycle (SDLC) methodologies and Agile techniques.



Work History

2019-10 -Current

Data Analyst

Koovs, Gurgaon, HARYANA

- Assessed KPIs to achieve in-depth understanding of campaign performance and Recommended performance improvements based on KPI analysis
- Collected affiliates data using various research methods to broaden results and optimize marketing strategies
- Forecasted marketing trends based on previous data to adjust campaigns and maximize conversion
- Recorded daily incoming data(Item type, affiliate conversion) in databases, streamlining analysis procedures for efficiency and accuracy

2017-08 -2019-10

Data Analyst

OYO, Gurgaon, HARYANA

- Performed system analysis, implementation and user support for platform transitions
- Handled tremendous volumes of customer data using tools/platforms like PostgreSQL, MySQL, Hive and Python. Performed analyses of input files to



Address

H.no 671, Sector 21 B Faridabad, Haryana, 121001

Phone

999-927-6527

E-mail

raja.himanshuu@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/9999276527/

WWW

https://github.com /himanshu6527



R



Python



SQL and Databases



Excellent

Microsoft Excel



Shiny Dashboards



Excellent

Automation



Big Query



Good

- derive data-driven insights and determine trends/errors using R
- Evaluated Revenue and Recovery trends to understand competitive environments and assess current strategies
- Automation of daily/weekly/monthly reports
 through automated mails and Google
 Spreadsheets which helps different teams to keep
 track of all performances
- Coordinated statistical data analysis, design, and information flow
- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs
- Synthesized current business intelligence data to produce reports and polished presentations highlighting findings and recommending changes
- Documented business workflows for stakeholder review
- Transformed project data requirements into project data models
- Successfully led key projects which resulted in increase of 3% in net profit

Product Support Analyst

OYO, Gurgaon, HARYANA

- Analyzed Platform and User Based issues to identify troubleshooting methods needed for quick remediation
- Worked with software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released software and assisted in deployment of release fixes
- Created support documentation that empowered and enabled user community to extend skills, leverage system features and find resolutions to questions without intervention from support team
- Broke down and evaluated user problems using test scripts, personal expertise and probing questions
- Managed transition of around 8k mobile devices from third party management to organization

Statistical and operational analysis

Very Good

Data Modeling



Planning



Research





RStudio



Microsoft Excel



Jupiter Notebook



2016-02 -2017-07



Education

2017-04 -

Data Science

2017-07

Analytix Lab - Gurgaon

2010-08 -2014-07 Bachelor of Technology: Electronics And Communications Engineering

Rawal Institution Of Engineeing And Technology - Fariadabad

2009-04 -

12th

2010-03

Kendriya Vidyalaya - Faridabad

2007-04 -

10th

2008-03

Kendriya Vidyalaya - Faridabad



Accomplishments



- Increased net Profit by 3% by spearheading and leading a comprehensive PnL campaign
- Consistently commended by upper management for spearheading and leading effective analysis automation



Interests

Sports

Workout

Traveling

Music

Gaming